Rare Pamphlet Collection 6034
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Rare Pamphlet Collection
1830-2005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
6034
28.5 cubic feet
27.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
5772831
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, March 21, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 24, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Adler, Victor, 1852-1918.; Alexander, Magnus W. (Magnus Washington), 1870-1932.; Bart, Phil.; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926.; Dunne, William F.; Edelman, Judy.; Falcone, Nicholas S.; Fichter, Joseph.; Firestone, Harvey S.; Floranski, W.; Frank, B.; Friedman, Israel E.; Glover, John G.; Haldeman-Julius, E. (Emanuel), 1888-1951.; Hansen, Beatrice, 1926- 1969.; Hathaway, C. A. (Clarence Albert), 1892-; Humble, John.; Kautsky, Karl.; Kollotai, Alexandra.; Lawrence, A. Susan.; Lovestone, Jay.; Lowy, David.; Luisi, Paulina.; MacDonald, Lois.; Martell, Edward.; Mathews, David G. J.; Mundy, E. W.; Napier, Jim.; North, Joseph.; O'Brien, Jo.; Petersen, Walter.; Proctor, Roscoe.; Purinton, Edward Earle.; Raske, Richard L.; Rogin, Lawrence, 1909-1988.; Simons, Henry C.; Stark, Louis.; Stockton, Richard.; Warbasse, Agnes D. (Agnes Dyer), 1877-1945.; Weiner, Sam.; Weisner, Beda.; Wells, Gabriel, 1862-1946; Williams, Albert L.; American Negro Labor Congress; Black Workers Congress; Bureau of Industrial Research; Consumers' League of New York City; Institute of International Labor Research; International Black Workers Congress; Public Affairs Committee; Research Council for Economic Security; Special Libraries Association; Student League for Industrial Democracy (U.S.); United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America; United States. Women's Bureau
5772831
- Box: 1, Folder: 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: A crime without a name, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Frederick Upham Adams
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
- Box: 1, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The evils disclosed by the coal strike, 1902; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Felix Adler
- Box: 1, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Die Arbeiterkammern und die Arbeiter, 1886; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Victor Adler
- Box: 1, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: African challenge, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: British Information Services
- Box: 1, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The Trucks Act: Michigan's blueprint for a fascist state, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: William Albertson
- Box: 1, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: An appraisal of the Federal social security act, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Winthrop W. Aldrich
- Box: 1, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Society's stepchildren fight back!: the story of the Scandinavian seamen in America, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Gus Alexander
- Box: 1, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Conference boards and their value in industrial co-operation, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Magnus W. Alexander
- Box: 1, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Labor parties of Latin America, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Robert Jackson Alexander
- Box: 1, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: The Story of the Algic case, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Algic Defense Committee
- Box: 1, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The cartel system, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: James S. Allen
  - Item 2: Revolutionary unionism!, 1914; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Allen, E. J. B.
- Box: 1, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: American Negro, 1932; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: Who owns America?, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Negro liberation, 1933; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Box: 1, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Working women's music, 1976; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Evelyn Alloy
- Box: 1, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: The bigot in our midst, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Gordon W. Allport
- Box: 1, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: All-Russian Union of Art Workers, All-Russian Union of Educational Workers / All-Russian Central Council of Trade Unions., 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: All-Russian Central Council of Trade Unions
  - Item 2: All-Russian Union of Treasury Employees, 1920; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: All- Russian Central Council of Trade Unions
- Box: 1, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: The Smith act and the supreme court, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union
  - Item 2: Justice for all: "Nor speak with double tongue," 37th annual report of the American Civil Liberties Union, 1957; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 3: Local civil liberties committees reports, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 4: Land of the pilgrim's pride, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 5: The gag on teaching: the story of the new restrictions by law on teaching in schools, and by public opinion and donors on colleges, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union.
  - Item 6: A labor union "Bill of Rights.", 1958; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 7: Laws vs. communists in schools and colleges, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 8: Freedom in wartime, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 9: Democracy in trade unions, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Box: 2, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Democracy in trade unions, 1946; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Liberty under the new deal: the record for 1933-1934, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: Liberty on the home front: in the fourth year of war., 1945; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: The Federal anti-injunction bill., 1931; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Even Adam had a hearing!: labor injunctions: what are they, why are they, what do they do to workers rights?, 1931; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Violence in Peekskill: a report of the violations of civil liberties at two Paul Robeson concerts near Peekskill, N.Y. August 27th and September 4th, 1949., Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Democracy in trade unions, 1943; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Who's un-American?: an answer to the "patriots.", 1939; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: The bill of rights 150 years after: the story of civil liberty, 1938-1939, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: The Conflict in the Illinois coal fields: memorandum prepared for submission to federal and state authorities., 1933; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Box: 2, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The Story of the Bertrand Russell case, 1941; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: In defense of our liberties: a report of the American civil liberties union in the third year of the war, 1944; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: What freedom for American students?, 1941; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: In the shadow of fear: American liberties 1948-1949., Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: The fight for civil liberty: The story of the Activities of the American Civil Liberties Union, 1928-1929., Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Eternal vigilance! The story of civil liberty, 1937-1938, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Call out the militia!: a survey of the use of troops in strikes, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Democracy in trade unions, Supplement, with desirable provisions from trade union by-laws, and references to court cases indicated in the report., 1943; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Academic freedom and academic responsibility: their meaning to students, teachers, administrators and the community, 1952; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Crisis at the University of California, 1949; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Author: American Civil Liberties Union of Northern California
  - Item 11: Crisis at the University of California, II, 1950; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Box: 2, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Important pamphlets on civil liberties, 1944; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 2: The menace of 'criminal syndicalism': war time repression by the federal government is continued through the states., Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: The story of civil liberty--1929-1930, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: It's not only communists' rights!, 1948; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: What rights for the unemployed?, 1935; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Democracy in trade unions: a survey, with a program of action., 1949; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 7: Academic freedom, academic responsibility, academic due process in institutions of higher learning, 1966; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 8: Black justice, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 9: The fight for civil liberty, 1927-1928: The story of the year 1927--of the courts, laws, police, schools, public opinion--with prospects ahead, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 10: Civil liberties of teachers and students, 1949; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 11: The struggle for civil liberties in the Illinois coal fields, 1933; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 12: Democracy in labor unions, 1958; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 13: The "Vanguard" problem at Brooklyn College, 1951; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Box: 2, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The activities of the Dies committee, 1940; Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Author: American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom
- Box: 2, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Handbook. American Labor Party, 1937; Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Author: American Labor Party
- Box: 2, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Why and how to boycott goods "made in Japan": questions and answers., 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Author: American League for Peace and Democracy
  - Item 2: Proceedings people's congress for democracy, 1938; Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Box: 3, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The American Legion and the communists discuss democracy: a debate., 1938; Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Box: 3, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Constitution and program of the American Negro Labor Congress: adopted at its First Annual Convention, Chicago, Ill., October 25-31, 1925., Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Author: American Negro Labor Congress
- Box: 3, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The American socialists and the war, 1917; Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Box: 3, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: American socialist quarterly, 1934; Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol. 3 no. 1, spring 1934.
- Box: 3, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: No forced labor camps for American youth!, 1941; Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Box: 3, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Declaration of principles and program for world trade., 1948; Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Author: American Tariff League
- Box: 3, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Toward an American revolutionary labor movement, 1934; Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Author: American Workers Party
- Box: 3, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Where do we go from here?: an examination of the record of the 14th National Convention CPUSA, 1948; Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Author: Americus
- Box: 3, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Labor and socialism in America, 1948; Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Box: 3, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Industrial revolution: some evidence from the reports of the Commission of Enquiry into Industrial Unrest, 1917; Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Author: Charles George Ammon
- Box: 3, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Industrial slavery: Roosevelts "New Deal", 1933; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Author: Israel Amter
  - Item 2: May Day 1939: for labor unity, for social and national security, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 3: A labor party for New York workers, 1935; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: Social security in a Soviet America, 1935; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 5: Why the workers' unemployment insurance bill?, 1933; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 6: Working class unity or fascism?, 1935; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Box: 3, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Types of social radicalism, 1927; Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Author: Benjamin M. Anderson
- Box: 3, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: A reading list of the American Federation of Labor, 1923; Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Author: Frank Anderson
- Box: 3, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Labor policy in the bituminous coal industry, 1922; Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Author: George J. Anderson
- Box: 3, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Parliament and trade union history, 1907; Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Author: W. C. Anderson
- Box: 3, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: The American farmer, 1932; Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Author: George Anstrom
- Box: 3, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Award of the Anthracite Coal Strike Commission, 1936; Publication (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Box: 3, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: There will come a day: imperialism and the working class, 1971; Publication (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Author: Gotfred Appel
- Box: 3, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The American civil war, 1961; Publication (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Author: Herbert Aptheker
  - Item 2: The labor movement in the South during slavery, 1955; Publication (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Box: 4, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The Taft-Hartley law: how it affects unions and workers, 1947; Publication (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Author: David I. Ashe
- Box: 4, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Havelock Wilson exposed, 1927; Publication (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Author: G. Atchkanov
- Box: 4, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Economic problems of the new deal, 1934; Publication (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Author: Willard E. Atkins
- Box: 4, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Local government and the socialist plan, Publication (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Author: C. R. Attlee
  - Item 2: Labour's aims in war and peace, 1940; Publication (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Box: 4, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Historical account of the Mollie Maguires and James "McKenna" McParlan, detective extraordinary, 1940; Publication (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Author: A. Monroe Aurand
- Box: 4, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Why does the auto union cause so much trouble in the automotive industry?, 1946; Publication (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Author: George Romney
- Box: 4, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Glory road to utopia, 1940; Publication (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Author: Seth Axley
- Box: 4, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Communist trade union trickery exposed, 1949; Publication (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Author: Karl Baarslag
  - Item 2: Communist trade union trickery exposed, 1947; Publication (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Box: 4, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Crises in European history, 1919; Publication (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Author: Gustav Bang
- Box: 4, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Economic fragments, 1934; Publication (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Author: James Bann
- Box: 4, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Riot of the unemployed at Trenton, N.J. 1935: a lecture at Harvard University, 1938-1941, presenting a case in concrete sociology, 1945; Publication (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Author: Chester Irving Barnard
- Box: 4, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: The farmers' way out: life under a workers and farmers government, 1935; Publication (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Author: John Barnett
- Box: 4, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Speeding up the workers, 1930; Publication (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Author: James Barnett
- Box: 4, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Let's join the human race, 1950; Publication (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Author: Stringfellow Barr
- Box: 4, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Labor's appeal for minimum wage and maximum hour law for North Carolina., 1939; Publication (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Author: James F. Barrett
- Box: 4, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Working Class Unity: The Role of Communists in the Chicago Federation of Labor, 1919-1923., 1975; Publication (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Author: Phil Bart
- Box: 4, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: A world history for the workers: a story of mans doings from the dawn of time, from the standpoint of the disinherited, 1926; Publication (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Author: Alfred Barton
- Box: 4, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Final recommendations, May 20, 1926, Publication (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Author: New York (State) Governor's Advisory Commission
- Box: 4, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: The red fraud: an expose of Stalinism, 1949; Publication (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Author: Fred Erwin Beal
- Box: 4, Folder: 20, Publication (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: The myth of rugged American individualism, 1932; Publication (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Author: Charles Austin Beard
- Box: 4, Folder: 21, Publication (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Labor's ascendancy, 1918; Publication (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Author: Anthony J. Beck
- Box: 4, Folder: 22, Publication (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Anti-soviet lies and the five-year plan; the "Holy" capitalist war against the Soviet Union, 1931; Publication (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Author: Max Bedacht
  - Item 2: Unity of the workers fraternal movement, 1936; Publication (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Box: 4, Folder: 23, Publication (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: What makes them tick?: a look at the men who man the trains, 1962; Publication (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Author: Duane Beeler
- Box: 4, Folder: 24, Publication (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: The parable of the water tank, 1902; Publication (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Author: Edward Bellamy
- Box: 4, Folder: 25, Publication (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: The movement for world trade union unity, 1925; Publication (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Author: Thomas Bell
- Box: 5, Folder: 1, Publication (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: The shirt waist strike, 1910; Publication (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Author: Charles Seligman Bernheimer
- Box: 5, Folder: 2, Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: The races of mankind, 1946; Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Author: Ruth Benedict
- Box: 5, Folder: 3, Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Unemployment and work, 1930; Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Author: Ernest J. P. Benn
- Box: 5, Folder: 4, Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: A workers' world, 1932; Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Author: David Paul Berenberg
- Box: 5, Folder: 5, Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: I saw Russia: socialism in the making, 1935; Publication (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Author: Mrs. Victor Berger
- Box: 5, Folder: 6, Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The Kronstadt rebellion, 1922; Publication (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Author: Alexander Berkman
- Box: 5, Folder: 7, Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Statement of facts in relation to the Lancaster Mills, 1851; Publication (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Author: Erastus B. Bigelow
- Box: 5, Folder: 8, Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Mistakes of the Interchurch steel report, 1920; Publication (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Author: E. Victor Bigelow
- Box: 5, Folder: 9, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Cease firing!: 1918-1940, Publication (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Author: Richard Bigelow
- Box: 5, Folder: 10, Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: What about the YWCA and labor?, 1946; Publication (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Author: Dorothy Hubbard Bishop
- Box: 5, Folder: 11, Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The American league against war and fascism, 1936; Publication (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Author: Hillman M. Bishop
- Box: 5, Folder: 12, Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Strikes and their related questions, 1886; Publication (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Author: Joel Prentiss Bishop
- Box: 5, Folder: 13, Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Problems of party building, 1937; Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Author: Alex Bittelman
  - Item 2: The communist party in action, 1934; Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Milestones in the history of the communist party, 1937; Publication (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Box: 5, Folder: 14, Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: References on the history of labor and some contemporary labor problems, 1893; Publication (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Author: J. William Black
- Box: 5, Folder: 15, Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: The Black liberation struggle, the Black Workers Congress and proletarian revolution: a comprehensive statement, 1974; Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Author: Black Workers Congress
  - Item 2: Manifesto of the Black Workers Congress, 1971; Publication (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Box: 5, Folder: 16, Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Detroit to Durban: black workers common struggle, 1973; Publication (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Author: Black Workers Organizing Committee
- Box: 5, Folder: 17, Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Merrie England, 1897; Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Author: Robert Blatchford
  - Item 2: A lesson for judges, or, the honest deserter, the gallant soldier, and the wicked trade unionist: a criticism of Mr. Justice Granthams unfair censure of the Bethesda strikers, 1901; Publication (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Box: 5, Folder: 18, Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Man of his century: a reconsideration of the historical significance of Karl Marx, 1943; Publication (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Author: Solomon F. Bloom
- Box: 5, Folder: 19, Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: What's ahead for textile workers, 1948; Publication (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Author: Emanuel Blum
- Box: 5, Folder: 20, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Bolchevisme et socialisme, Publication (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Author: Leon Blum
    Language: French.
- Box: 5, Folder: 21, Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: A blueprint for fascism: what the industrial mobilization plan holds for America, 1937; Publication (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Author: Frank B. Blumenfield
- Box: 5, Folder: 22, Publication (Box 5, Folder 22)